Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
- Burney, Charles, 1757-1817. Autograph letter, signed, Greenwich (London, England), to [Edmond Malone] 1798 Aug. 22., (82); 1s.
  Sends biographical research on poet John Dryden.
- Burney, Charles, 1757-1817. Commission: manuscript document, [no place] 1810 May 6., (83); 1s.
  Appointment as chaplain to George III, King of Great Britain. Signed and sealed by Vere Warner, usher to the king.
- Burney, James, 1750-1821. Autograph letter, signed, 26 James Street, Westminster (London), to Mr. Allen, 1812 Jan. 15., (84); 2s.
  Concerning Alexander von Humboldt's comments on Aaron Arrowsmith. With cover.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 45.
- Burney, Martin Charles, 1788-1852. Autograph letter, signed, 26 James Street [Westminster, London] to Charlotte Barrett, 1838 Sept. 25., (85); 1s.
  Concerning the death of his aunt Charlotte Anne Francis, the recipient's mother.
- Bute, John Stuart, Marquess of, 1744-1814 (then Viscount Mountstuart). Autograph letter, signed, Rome, to William Mure, 1765 June 5., (86); 2s.
  Wants to continue travels with James Boswell, and asks Mure to ask Alexander Boswell, Lord Auchinleck, for permission. With typescript transcript.
  *2003JM-57.
- Butterfield, William, 1814-1900. Autograph letter, signed, 4 Adam Street, Adelphi [London] to Charles Edward Burney, 1884 Dec. 19., (87); 1s.
  Describes a commemoration of the centenary of the death of Samuel Johnson at the St. Clements Danes Church in London.
- Buxton [?], Francis. Letter, signed, Blakenham [Suffolk, England] to William Strahan, 1775 Oct. 4., (88); 1s.
  Comments on Samuel Johnson's abilities as a sportsman.
- Byng, Robert, 1703-1740. Letter, signed, Treasury Office for the Navy [London] to Patrick Gordon, 1726 Oct. 28., (89); 1s.
  Sends Isaac Miranda to handle Admiralty business in Pennsylvania.
- Byron, George Anson, 1758-1793. Autograph letter, signed, Bristol Channel, to [John Wodehouse, Baron Wodehouse] 1792 Jan. 25., (90); 1s.
  Describes his illness and return to England from India.
- Cadell, T. (Thomas), 1742-1802. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Jane Johnston Millar, 1769 July 21., (91); 1s.
  Describes the conditions of Mr. Gray's will.
- [Cagliostro], Alessandro, conte di, 1743-1795. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Seraphina Cagliostro?] [17--] Mar. 16., (92); 1s.
  In Italian.
- Cambridge, Adolphus Frederick, Duke of, 1774-1850. Autograph letter, signed, Cambridge House [London] to unidentified recipient, 1848 July 15., (93); 1s.
  Solicits funds for a sub-committee which he chairs.
- Camden, John Jeffreys Pratt, Marquis of, 1759-1840. Autograph letter, signed, Arlington Street [London?] to [George Hammond?] 1801 Feb. 20., (94); 1s.
  Sends a cabinet box and key.
- Camden, John Jeffreys Pratt, Marquis of, 1759-1840. Order to pay: document, signed, [no place] 1806 Sept. 25., (95); 1s.
  Order to pay Thomas Bidwell. With attached receipt signed by Bidwell.
- Camden, John Jeffreys Pratt, Marquis of, 1759-1840. Order to pay: document, signed, [no place] 1806 Sept. 25., (96); 1s.
  Order to pay Radcliffe Medley. Also signed by John Courtenay,; Charles Watkin Williams Wynn, and others. With attached receipt, signed, from A. Cowper to Lord Camden.
- Camden, John Jeffreys Pratt, Marquis of, 1759-1840. Order to pay: document, signed, [no place] 1806 Nov. 3., (97); 1s.
  Order to pay Sir Robert Graham. Also signed by John Courtenay,; William Wickham,; Charles Watkin Williams Wynn, and others. An attached receipt has been torn off.
- Campbell, John, 1708-1775. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] [not after 1774], (98); 1s.
  Receipt to Thomas Buchan of Auchmacoy [Aberdeenshire, Scotland] for a subscription to Campbell's A Political Survey of Britain.
- Campbell, John Campbell, Baron, 1779-1861. Autograph letter, signed, Stratheden House [Knightsbridge] to Sir Anthony Panizzi, [not before 1837] Tuesday., (99); 1s.
  Seeking English translations of the works of William Fitzstephen (d. 1190?). Probably written after Panizzi was appointed Keeper of Printed Books at the British Museum in 1837.
- Campbell, John Campbell, Baron, 1779-1861. Autograph letter, signed, Stratheden House [Knightsbridge] to Rev. J.T. Smith, 1849 Apr. 19., (100); 1s.
  Expresses interest in seeing Smith's manuscript.
- Campbell, John Campbell, Baron, 1779-1861. Legal file: autograph manuscript, signed, Temple [London] 1823 July 4., (101); 2s.
  Opinion in the case of Skerrington vs. William Green, concerning the sale of coal.
- Campbell, Thomas, 1777-1844. Buonparte and the British Sailor: autograph manuscript draft poem, signed, [ca. 1800?], (102); 2s.
  Historical poem concerning a captured sailor who was paroled by Napoleon I, Emperor of the French, to be reunited with his mother.
  Published as Napoleon and the British Sailor in Lewis Campbell, ed., Poems of Thomas Campbell (London: MacMillan and Co., 1904), 224-227.
- Carey, Mathew, 1760-1839. Autograph letter, signed, [Philadelphia, Pennsylvania?] to Nicholas Biddle, 1816 Dec. 6., (103); 1s.
  Concerning copyright for History of the Expedition under the Command of Captains Lewis and Clark.
- Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881. Autograph note, signed, Chelsea [London] to unidentified recipient, 1846 Apr. 16., (104); 1s.
  Reads in its entirety: "Beware of Counterfeits! T. Carlyle, Chelsea, 16 April, 1846."
- Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881. Samuel Johnson: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] [1853], (105); 1s.
  Final draft of the title pages of Carlyle's biography of Samuel Johnson, with instructions to the printer (Chapman and Hall of London).
  *2003JM-64.
- Carter, Elizabeth, 1717-1806. 4 letters, to Susanna Highmore Duncombe, 1750-1801., (106); 6s.
  The 1750 June 4 letter discusses Mrs. (Mary) Leapor. The 1795 May 21 letter praises Margaret Georgiana Poyntz Spencer, Countess Spencer. The 1801 Mar. 2 letter discusses the estate of Eliza Berkeley. The 1801 May 29 letter discusses the mental illness of a Mrs. Blomer. With a 19th-century manuscript transcript of the 1750 letter, and a cover sheet dated 1869 describing the provenance.
- Cathcart, Charles Schaw Cathcart, Lord, 1721-1776. Autograph letter, signed, Moffat [Dumfries-shire, Scotland] to unidentified recipient, 1760 July 23., (107); 1s.
  Seeking patronage for a new position.
- Catherine II, Empress of Russia, 1729-1796. Printed document, signed, 1789., (108); 1s.
  In Russian.
- Cave, [Thomas] Autograph letter, signed, Stanford Hall [Leicestershire, England] to James Dodsley, 1767 Aug. 30., (109); 1s.
  Describes plans to sue Dodsley for libel.
- Cay, John, 1700-1757. Case of the Proprietors of Johnson's English Dictionary: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] 1755 Oct. 15., (110); 1s.
  Signed autograph legal opinion by Cay, appended to a description in an unknown hand of a new edition of N. (Nathan) Bailey's A New Universal Etymological English Dictionary, alleged to plagiarize Samuel Johnson's Dictionary of the English Language.
- Chalmers, Alexander, 1759-1834. Autograph letter, signed, [London] to H. Foss, [1830 Nov. 29] Monday., (111); 1s.
  Reports on the final illness of an unidentified friend.
- Chalmers, Alexander, 1759-1834. Autograph letter, signed, Throgmorton Street [London] to unidentified recipient, 1815 May 25., (112); 1s.
  Sends autographs.
- Chalmers, Alexander, 1759-1834. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1829 June] Saturday., (113); 1s.
  Concerning plans for the royal coaches.
- Chalmers, George, 1742-1825. Autograph note, Green Street [London] to Lackington, Allen and Co., 1808 July 12., (114); 1s.
  Order for two books.
- Chambers, Anne Metcalfe, 1713-1782. 2 autograph letters, signed, to her son Sir Robert Chambers, 1755-1767. Sept. 30., (115); 2s.
  The 1755 Sept. 30 letter concerns efforts to dispose of the lease and furnishings of a family home. On the verso, a related autograph draft letter from Sir Robert Chambers to Mr. Cock. The 1767 Mar. 31 letter consists of family news.
- [Chambers, Frances Wilton, Lady, 1759-1839?] Autograph letter, [no place] to Charles Manners-Sutton (then Archbishop of Canterbury), 1819 Sept. 18., (116); 1s.
  Retained copy. Seeks support for charitable efforts. Quotes Samuel Johnson.
- [Chambers, Frances Wilton, Lady, 1759-1839?] Autograph letter, [London?] to William Parker (1714-1802), [between 1791-1802] September 21., (117); 1s.
  Retained copy. Describes charitable efforts among the London poor. Written after her return from India in 1791. Mentions Samuel Johnson.
- Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871. Autograph letter, signed, South Coates [Edinburgh, Scotland] to John Edward Dove, 1839 May 1., (118); 1s.
  Discusses animal magnetism.
- Chambers, Robert, Sir, 1737-1803. Autograph letter, signed, London, to his mother Anne Metcalfe Chambers, 1773 Aug. 3., (119); 1s.
  Describes plans to accompany Samuel Johnson on the first leg of his voyage to Scotland.
- Chambers, Robert, Sir, 1737-1803. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Sir Philip Francis, 1780 Oct. 25., (120); 2s.
  Concerning a position for which Chambers's brother was passed over. Includes cover.
- Chambers, William, Sir, 1723-1796. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Benjamin West, [ca. 1782-1796] Friday., (121); 1s.
  Recommends admission of young William Lock (1767-1847) to their dinner group.
- Chandler, Richard, 1738-1810. Autograph letter, signed, Magdalen College, Oxford (England), to unidentified recipient, 1774 June 26., (122); 1s.
  Concerning foreign sales of his Inscriptiones Antiquae.
- Chandos, Lydia Catherina Brydges, Duchess of, 1693-1750. Autograph letter, signed, Shaw [Berkshire, England] to her stepson Henry Brydges, Duke of Chandos (then Marquess of Carnarvon), 1749 Oct. 19., (123); 1s.
  Discusses Elizabeth Robinson Montagu.
- Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649. Order: manuscript document, signed, Beverley (England), 1642 July 16., (124); 1s.
  Scale of payment for troops, addressed to Edward Walker, paymaster. Thought to be formerly owned by James Boswell.
- Charles II, King of England, 1630-1685. Order: manuscript document, signed, Whitehall [London] 1673 Jan. 13., (125); 1s.
  Order to "the principall officers and commanders of our Navy" to refit HMS Roebuck. Countersigned by Samuel Pepys.
- Charles XII, King of Sweden, 1682-1718. Document, signed, 1706 Dec. 1., (126); 1s.
  In Swedish.
- Charles Emmanuel III, King of Sardinia, 1701-1773. Letter, signed, Turin (Italy), to Commendatore di Bartolo, 1755 Sept. 21., (127); 1s.
  Military orders. In Italian.
- Chatterton, Thomas, 1752-1770. Autograph letter, signed, Redclift Hill, Bristol (England), to James Dodsley, 1768 Dec. 21., (128); 3s.
  Offers to send poems by "Thomas Rowley" for publication. Signed as "D.B." (Dunhelmus Bristoliensis). With cover, and a manuscript in an approximation of Old English, possibly a "Thomas Rowley" composition but apparently not an enclosure with this letter.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 61.
- Chatterton, Thomas, 1752-1770. Sly Dick: autograph manuscript, [1764], (129); 2s.
  Juvenile poem. Also includes his A Hymn for Christmas Day.
- Chatto, William Andrew, 1799-1864. Autograph letter, signed, Agar Place, Camden Town [London] to Robert Balmanno, 1843 Jan. 30., (130); 24 pages (sewn into three signatures of 4 leaves each).
  Discusses his efforts to publish Love Letters of Mrs. Piozzi, Written When She was Eighty, to William Conway. Credits Balmanno with the supply of William Conway anecdotes and the discovery of the letters.
- Chenevix, Richard, 1697-1779 (then Bishop of Waterford). Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to Rev. Dr. Austin of Cork (Ireland), 1773 Oct. 19., (131); 2s.
  Concerning a charity founded by Moses Deane. With cover.
- Chisolm, Alexander. Autograph note, signed, [London?] to J. (John) Nourse, [1755?] Apr. 18., (132); 1s.
  Requesting a copy of Samuel Johnson's Dictionary of the English Language on behalf of his employer William Lewis (1708-1781).
- Cholmondeley, George James Cholmondeley, Marquess of, 1749-1827. Autograph letter, signed, Piccadilly [London] to unidentified recipient, 1787 Feb. 23., (133); 1s.
  Concerning payments to Mrs. Elliot, and a newspaper subscription.
- Churton, Ralph, 1754-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Middleton, near Banbury (Oxfordshire, England), to [William] Ford, 1810 Apr. 19., (134); 1s.
  Orders two books from Ford's catalog.
- Churton, Ralph, 1754-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Middleton, near Banbury (Oxfordshire, England), to John Thomas Smith (1766-1833), 1807 July 14., (135); 1s.
  Correcting an error in Smith's Antiquities of Westminster.
- Cibber, Colley, 1671-1757. Facsimile autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1750 Dec. 25., (136); 1s.
  Has been ill, desires a visit. Engraved facsimile.
- Cipriani, Giovanni Battista, 1766-1839. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [18--?], (137); 1s.
- Clairaut, [M., 1713-1765?] Autograph letter, signed, Rue du long St. Jean, Paris, to Samuel Richardson, 1754 Nov. 4., (138); 1s.
  Concerning the French translation of Richardson's Sir Charles Grandison by the abbé Prévost.
- Clarendon, Edward Hyde, Earl of, 1609-1674. 2 autograph letters, signed, Hague (Netherlands), to Charles II, King of England, 1630-1685 (then Prince Regent), [1648], (139); 2s.
  The Oct. 11 Friday letter concerns finances for the royalist resistance. The Dec. 1 Tuesday letter concerns commissions, and discusses a forthcoming order from Sir William Boswell to shut the sluices at the Hague.
- Clive, Robert Clive, Baron, 1725-1774. Autograph letter, signed, Berkeley Square [London] to unidentified recipient, [17--] Sunday morning., (140); 1s.
  Seeks advice concerning an election contested by a Mr. Waring.
- Clough, Arthur Hugh, 1819-1861. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [John William] Parker, [1859] Mar. 16 Wednesday., (141); 1s.
  Concerning the publication of Florence Nightingale's Notes on Hospitals.
- Clow, James. Autograph letter, signed, Glasgow (Scotland), to [Robert Foulis?] 1776 May 30., (142); 1s.
  Concerning a publication by Robert Simson, probably his Opera Quaedam Reliqua, published by R. A. Foulis.
- Cobbett, William, 1763-1835. Autograph letter, signed, Duke Street [London?] to George Henry Glasse, [1805?] Mar. 24., (143); 1s.
  Reports on the health of his daughter.
- Colleton, Elizabeth. Will: manuscript document, Ealing (England), 1721 June 26., (144); 2s.
  Last will and testament, on parchment. Colleton was a spinster of Ealing. Heirs included her brother Sir John Colleton and his children; and the family of her illegitimate daughter, Elizabeth Savage van Nassau van Zuylestein, Countess Rochford. Part of the daughter's inheritance is contingent upon her naming a son after Richard Savage.
- Colman, George, 1762-1836. Autograph letter, signed, Rose Hill Cottage, Greenford, Middlesex (England), to Mr. Smith, [ca. 1832], (145); 1s.
  Discusses the correspondence of David Garrick.
- Colman, George, 1762-1836. Verses for an album, written at the request of the Countess of Blessington: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] 1819 Aug. 1., (146); 1s.
  Poem written for Marguerite, Countess of Blessington.
- Conway, William Augustus, 1789-1828. Autograph letter, signed, Bath (England), to Sir James Fellowes, 1821 May 7., (147); 1s.
  Sends Fellowes a draft from the late Hester Lynch Piozzi, payable to Conway. Appended is Fellowes's manuscript transcript of the draft, dated 1820 May 29, with his note on its disposition.
- Cooke, Thomas, 1703-1756. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1732 Nov. 8., (148); 1s.
  Asks for the return of extra books; has recently returned from "your side of the water." May be addressed to Cooke's Dublin publisher George Faulkner.
- Cooke, William. Agreement: autograph document, signed, 1772 May 8., (149); 1s.
  Agreement with George Kearsley to expand Cooke's poem The Senators.
- Cooper, F.C. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to the British Institution, [18--?], (150); 1s.
  Asks that "my picture from Rasselas" be delivered to Henry Mogford.
- Cork and Orrery, Mary Monckton Boyle, Countess of, 1746-1840 (then Miss Monckton). Autograph note, [no place] to James Boswell, [not after 1786], (151); 2s.
  Invitation to visit. With cover.
- Cornwallis, Charles Cornwallis, Marquis, 1738-1805. Autograph letter, signed, Calcutta (India), to William Wyndham Grenville, Baron Grenville, 1789 Mar. 10., (152); 1s.
  Discusses English politics and the prosperous state of affairs in India.
- Cornwallis, Charles Cornwallis, Marquis, 1738-1805. Autograph letter, signed, Calford near Bury [Suffolk, England] to George Hammond, 1804 Jan. 17., (153); 1s.
  Seeks the parole of a French prisoner named d'Aumont, possibly Louis-Alexandre-Céleste, duc d'Aumont.
- Cowper, William, 1731-1800. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to John Newton (1725-1807), 1784 Mar. 19., (154); 1s.
  Offers a long meditation on despair. Has been reading Samuel Johnson's Lives of the English Poets, and observes that "poets are a very worthless, wicked set of people."
- Cowper, William, 1731-1800. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to William Cawthorne Unwin (1745-1786), 1785 Dec. 6., (155); 1s.
  Describes a visit from [Lewis?] Bagot.
- Coxe, William, 1747-1828. Autograph note, signed, Bemerton [Wiltshire, England] to John Paterson, treasurer of the Governors of Queen Anne's Bounty (Great Britain), 1814 Aug. 7., (156); 1s.
  Sends certificate.
- Crabbe, George, 1754-1832. Autograph letter, signed, Trowbridge (England), to his son John Waldron Crabbe, 1826 Apr. 13., (157); 1s.
  Family news.
- Craig, W. M. (William Marshall), ca. 1765-ca. 1834. Proposal: autograph manuscript, signed, 88 Charlotte St., Rathbone Place [London] 1793 Feb., (158); 1s.
  Proposal to explore the possibility of creating a mutual society for painters.
- Craufurd, John Walkinshaw, ca. 1721-1793. 2 autograph letters, signed, Crawfordland [Ayrshire, Scotland] to James Boswell, 1786 Apr. 20 and 29., (159); 2s.
  Responses to Boswell's Letter to the People of Scotland.
- Craven, Elizabeth Craven, Baroness, 1750-1828. Autograph letter, signed, Brandenburg[-Ansbach (Margraviate)] to Mr. Parke, 1818 July 27., (160); 1s.
  Asks Parke, the English consul at Rome, to get customs fees waived for her home furnishings.
- Craven, Elizabeth Craven, Baroness, 1750-1828. Indenture: autograph document, signed, Triesdorf near Anspach [Ansbach] (Mittelfranken, Germany), 1788 Sept. 20., (161); 1s.
  Granting Charles Andrew Mercier the exclusive right to the journal of her travels, published as A Journey through the Crimea to Constantinople.
- Craven, Elizabeth Craven, Baroness, 1750-1828. Indenture: manuscript document, [no place] 1788 Nov. 7., (162); 1s.
  Assignment of rights to Lady Craven's A Journey through the Crimea to Constantinople from Charles Andrew Mercier to George Robinson Co. Signed and sealed by Mercier and Robinson, and witnessed by John St. Coman.
- Craven, William Craven, Baron, 1737 or 8-1791. Autograph letter, signed, Combe Abbey [Coventry, England] to unidentified recipient, 1771 Aug. 26., (163); 1s.
  Offers congratulations on marriage, and sends evidence concerning a property dispute.
- Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811. Autograph letter, signed, [Tunbridge Wells, England] to Sir James Bland Burges, [1801] Thursday., (164); 1s.
  Comments on the death of Edward Riou and other current events.
- Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1789 Feb.?] Tuesday., (165); 1s.
  Mentions "the Club" (the Literary Club?),; Charles James Fox, and the recovery of George III, King of Great Britain.
- Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [17--?] Sunday., (166); 1s.
  Mentions "the Club" (the Literary Club?) and William Beloe's Alfred Club.
- Cumberland, Richard, 1732-1811. Autograph letter, signed, Tunbridge Wells (England), to unidentified recipient, [17--] Apr. 11., (167); 1s.
  Solicits comments on his new play.
- Cunningham, Alexander, 1655?-1730. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1717 Jan. 8., (168); 1s.
  Receipt for annuity, made out to teller Richard Hampden. Also signed by witness Thomas Snow.
- Currie, James, 1756-1805. Autograph letter, signed, Liverpool (England), to [Francis Trench] 1789 Sept. 1., (169); 6s.
  Describes Hester Lynch Piozzi and Gabriele Mario Piozzi at length. Also discusses the Liverpool theatrical scene, Adam Lymburner, and Adam Kippis. With typed transcript.
- Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Newhailes [near Musselburgh, Scotland] to James Boswell, 1779 July 9., (170); 1s.
  Commenting on Lives of the English Poets by Samuel Johnson, and furnishing description of John Dryden.
- Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to unidentified recipient, 1769 Dec. 11., (171); 2s.
  Asks for assistance in distributing tracts; with a possibly unrelated list of recipients.
- Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Newhailes near Edinburgh (Scotland), to unidentified recipient, 1782 Oct. 24., (172); 1s.
  Forwarding a parcel of books from Thomas Falconer.
- Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Newhailes near Edinburgh (Scotland), to unidentified recipient, 1791 Oct. 28., (173); 1s.
  Offers corrections, possibly for a new edition of James Granger's A Biographical History of England.
- Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792. Remarks of Lord Hailes on Dr. Johnson's Lives: autograph manuscript, [no place] [1779?], (174); 6 leaves, mounted on one sheet.
  Detailed commentary on Samuel Johnson's Lives of the English Poets. On verso, autograph manuscript registration by James Boswell, providing the title and commenting "they begin with Vol. 3 of the Preface Edition for which we see the last page." Mounted on a sheet with manuscript notes in an unknown hand, describing the contents.
- Davies, Thomas, ca. 1712-1785. 2 autograph letters, signed, London, to [James Granger] 1769 and undated., (175); 3s.
  Discussing Granger's A Biographical History of England. The Oct. 21 letter discusses the acquittal of Giuseppe Marco Antonio Baretti. The undated letter offers for sale a used copy of Samuel Johnson's Dictionary of the English Language, and includes a typescript transcript.
  Partial transcript of the 1769 Oct. 21 letter in Adam, 80.
- Davies, Thomas, ca. 1712-1785. Autograph letter, signed, London, to J. (James) Robertson, 1772 Apr. 13., (176); 2s.
  Describes a visit by Samuel Johnson and James Boswell to the Davies shop. Mentions that Boswell has read Robertson's Poems: Consisting of Tales, Fables, Epigrams, c., and may visit Robertson in York (England). With typed transcript.
- Dawson, George, 1821-1876. Autograph letter, signed, Birmingham (England), to unidentified recipient, [18--] June 11., (177); 1s.
  Confirming appearance.
- De Morgan, Augustus, 1806-1871. Autograph letter, signed, 7 [City?] Street [London?] to [Thomas Kibble] Hervey, 1848 Nov. 28., (178); 1s.
  Discusses Charles Babbage and an article he wishes to reprint in The Athenaeum.
- De Quincey, Thomas, 1785-1859. London reminiscences, chapter I: autograph manuscript, [no place] [18--], (179); 1s.
  Fragment of a draft, with heavy corrections. Compares Samuel Johnson with Samuel Taylor Coleridge, and discusses the role of the intellectual in an aristocracy. Paginated "EE" and "FF." Title written in a different hand.
  Published as part of Literary Reminiscences of Thomas De Quincey (Boston: Ticknor, Reed and Fields, 1851), 44-46.
- Defoe, Daniel, 1661?-1731. Autograph letter, signed, Newington near Hackney [London] to Thomas Wharton, Marquess of Wharton, 1710 Apr. 7., (180); 4s.